(Respect copyright)
♪Memories hold you back
from fulfilling your dreams♪
♪Only by moving forward
can you find reunion♪
♪Endings only mark new routes♪
♪It's all part of the scenery♪
♪To the horizon's call♪
♪Your journey hasn't started♪
♪Towards mountains,
chase the stars bright♪
♪Let time embrace you
and wash away the past♪
♪Put every twist behind you♪
♪Drift leisurely through time♪
♪Make headway against the wind♪
♪Let mountains bow to your pace♪
♪Rush towards a life without regret♪
♪Let your nature burst free♪
=The First Jasmine=
=Episode 5=
In the matter of Lu Changfu,
I can relieve Your Majesty's worries.
But I have three requests.
First,
while I clear the obstacles
on your path,
please support me
in clearing the name of Heiyun Cavalry,
Prince Ding's household,
and my elder brother.
Back then, General Xiuwen said
he returned
by the late Emperor's decree,
but he couldn't present it.
That's why...
Without that imperial decree,
this case can't be overturned.
When I was imprisoned,
Marquis Muyang told me
he destroyed the decree.
How dare he?
Do you trust me?
I trust you, Xiuyao.
There might be a chance
to root out Marquis Muyang.
Okay.
I grant your request.
If Marquis Muyang remains,
there's no peace for the court.
Second,
I request the authority
for investigation.
I request the access to review
all archived files in the Six Ministries,
and the power to interrogate
anyone involved in any case.
I request the authority to make arrests.
Officials of the fifth rank
or lower involved
can be imprisoned directly
in the Imperial Prison.
Also, the privilege
to submit secret memorials.
So I can send secret news
and intelligence
gathered in the capital straight to you.
Third,
I want one person.
Lady.
It's our osmanthus cakes.
Fluffy and refreshing.
Even the Prefect's lady wants them.
Alright.
Please.
(Qingfeng Mingyue Tower)
If Lu Changfu really makes it to Huaixi,
there's no hope left
for the weaponry case.
Taking Marquis Muyang down
will be more difficult.
The Emperor made it clear.
Lu Changfu
must not leave the capital alive.
Good.
Then kill him.
Poison, sword, fire or water?
Which method do you prefer?
Lu Changfu has committed countless sins.
Though we cannot
deal with him by law at present,
he must die.
Xiuyao, what do you think?
In my opinion,
since he must die,
why not let him die
before the officials,
beneath the open sky?
But Mother...
This is ultimately your world.
Yet Marquis Muyang
has the Eight Evils in his faction,
Zhou Chengxiang, Wen Zhong, and Lv Cheng
are now captured and executed.
That Lu Changfu would be dead soon.
Then, do we still kill the others?
All who have owed a debt of blood
certainly deserve death.
Are you sure?
If we killed Lu Changfu,
Marquis Muyang will surely retaliate.
Considering the state
of Prince Ding's house before,
and my circumstances now,
why fear his retaliation?
Your circumstances now?
You are married,
and have a Princess Consort.
Ye Li.
You're free to go now.
To where?
Anywhere you like.
You married me just to leave Lishan.
Now, we've been married awhile.
I could tell the Empress Dowager
that you and I
cannot get along well
and plead for a divorce.
You could return to the Ye Mansion
or leave the capital.
Go to anywhere you desire.
Why stare at me?
You seem strange today.
Always urge me to leave,
even saying any place will do.
Are you planning rebellion?
Nonsense!
I just mean well.
Then, drink this soup up.
Or I have to rewarm it when it cools.
If you're doing this to repay
my life-saving grace in the desert,
those pastries you gave me
in the prison cart
have repaid it.
After all, without the pastries,
I wouldn't survive the prison life.
You remember me?
You never mentioned it.
I thought you'd forgotten.
On our wedding day,
you said "Nice to meet you."
Wasn't it you who'd forgotten?
When did you remember me?
Did you recognize me right away,
or did it come to you later?
I'm talking to you about the divorce.
What I'm asking is also important.
Since we both want
to ask the other first,
why not let the fate decide?
If the characters "Xide Tongbao"
land facing up,
I'll do it your way
and talk about the divorce.
But if the coin comes down tails,
then you'll do my way.
Let's talk about when you remembered me.
Alright.
Then let's follow the fate.
We'll talk about the past first,
then the divorce.
Tell me, when did you remember me?
Five watches at the Yin hour.
Sleep early, rise early.
Care for your health.
(Lu Mansion)
(Three quarters past the Yin hour
is the court session.)
From Chongren Lane,
via Yanximen Street, to the imperial city.
In such a long route,
no matter how cautious,
one will reveal weak spots.
We could set an ambush ahead.
When he passes, we'll unleash the bolts,
ensuring his death.
Difficult.
Do you know?
Lu Changfu's carriage
is no ordinary carriage.
(It seems mundane,)
(but actually,)
(inside is layers of elm wood
sandwiching fine steel.)
(Furthermore, it's guarded by experts.)
We could take action,
but if that strike fails,
it will only make him vigilant.
It won't be easy to strike again.
(Danque Gate)
(From Daming Palace's Longwei Path
to Danque Gate,)
(officials disarm and enter on foot.)
(Within Imperial Palace,
Lu Changfu cannot bring any guards.)
(Once the court adjourns,)
(it's time for the imperial guards
changing shifts.)
(Besides, the security here is weak.)
Perfect for killing him.
Good.
Then our people
set ambush atop tall buildings.
Lord Lu.
Good.
Congrats!
Military Governor Lu.
Congrats, Military Governor Lu!
Congrats...
No.
Military Governor Lu.
(Lu Changfu)
Right. Someone from Ye family came,
asking you to go attend
the reunion banquet
for Madam's birthday next month.
Reunion banquet?
Your Majesty.
Empress Dowager.
Marquis Muyang is unwell,
so absent today.
In capital region, four high ministers
have fallen consecutively.
Jingzhao Prefecture has investigated
tirelessly, but found nothing.
I am
too ashamed to hold this position.
Punish me, Your Majesty.
Magistrate Gongshu, don't say that.
Bandits rise all over.
First, they killed Yuan Fang.
Then, they slew four ministers.
Their ferocity is evident.
Magistrate Gongshu,
how could you prevent it?
I cannot blame you alone.
You've been in charge
of Jingzhao Prefecture for six years,
and righted thirty-six
wrongful convictions.
Both Mother and I
are well aware of this.
Never mention the punishment again.
Mother, what do you think?
You speak truth.
Thank you for your grace and kindness.
Your Majesty.
Empress Dowager.
Huaixi is the key
to control the Jianghuai region.
With Military Governor
Lu Changfu now dead,
I suggest to fill role with talent soon.
Any recommendation?
I have a candidate to recommend.
I believe Gongshu Yang
suits this position.
In Xide's Fifth Year,
chaos broke out in Huaizhou Army.
He was once the Magistrate
of Jingzhao Prefecture,
overseeing the grain shipment there.
He shattered thirteen bands
of water bandits, truly a capable officer.
Minister Gongshu truly
boasts notable achievements.
Moreover, he was elevated by Mother.
He is a man of honor.
Though Huaixi is perilous today,
it precisely requires
a devoted minister like him.
What do you think, Mother?
Makes sense.
Minister Gongshu,
will you accept this appointment?
I
accept.
I'll do whatever you say,
Your Majesties.
Good.
Draft an edict.
- Yes.
Promote Gongshu Yang
from Jingzhao Prefecture
to Honorary Minister of War,
and appoint him
as Military Governor of Huaixi.
Bestow upon him Linfu Golden Armor.
In three days,
he departs to assume office.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty,
as Magistrate Gongshu rises
to become Military Governor of Huaixi,
we need a new Magistrate
of Jingzhao Prefecture.
It also requires a suitable candidate.
You speak well.
I think in these times
of rampant banditry,
the successor must
have military experience
to intimidate such petty villains.
Do you have a recommendation?
Prince Ding,
Mo Xiuyao.
The Mingde Hall today was quite lively.
Murong Shen recommended you
as Magistrate of Jingzhao Prefecture.
Zhang Hengyuan was the first to refute.
He said you...
He said
that you're a cripple
and a condemned sinner,
unfit for such a crucial post.
And other members
of Marquis Muyang's faction
said you've stayed indoors
for many years
and are solitary,
shunning all company,
couldn't manage the affairs
of Jingzhao Prefecture
and secure the peace
throughout the capital well.
No need to state everything
in such detail.
I'm just worried
I might not convey it clearly.
Don't interrupt.
At this critical moment,
guess what happened?
Jin, make a guess.
The Duke Hua stood up
and supported you.
Duke Hua?
Yes.
Duke Hua.
He hadn't spoken at court in years.
But somehow he chose today to speak up.
Murong Shen and Marquis Muyang's faction
were in a constant quarrel,
with no resolution.
But Duke Hua represents
the military might of Dachu.
The moment he spoke,
the tide instantly turned.
He sent the losing faction
stumbling into the city moat,
so they couldn't resist.
Then you were confirmed.
The Empress Dowager said nothing?
Perhaps she deferred to the Duke Hua.
Wrong.
Though the Marquis Muyang once basked
in the Empress Dowager's favor,
he's ancient history now.
The current favorite is Gongshu Yang.
Though the young emperor
handed over Huaixi to him,
the Empress Dowager couldn't object.
The young emperor's open scheme
is truly awe-inspiring!
As the emperor, one must be capable.
As if you attended court yourself today.
Sitting at home,
I can still get the news.
That is my skill.
But we didn't
kill Lu Changfu.
Who did it?
The emperor said anything?
If it was one persecuted by Lu Changfu
and committed no further evils,
he could be pardoned.
Well, this individual
is truly impressive.
If you find him,
perhaps let him join us.
Right.
The capital's new magistrate
is soon to take office.
How do you think?
I think you've been here far too long.
Time to go.
I heard a few days ago,
the Princess Consort
set your study on fire?
The loss must be significant.
What a temper she has!
Feng Zhiyao,
you plant spies in my residence?
You sure have some guts.
I wouldn't dare.
Where's the Princess Consort?
She went out early this morning.
(Tomb of Seven Martyrs of Lishan)
(Former Teachers and Friends of Lishan)
Lu Changfu framed you incited trouble,
and had you all burned alive.
Now that justice has been served.
Rest in peace.
Are you okay?
You ate too much this morning?
I didn't have breakfast at all.
It's the boatman's fault.
The constant swaying
back and forth made me dizzy.
We're leaving soon.
Aren't you going
to say something to them?
No need.
Let's go home.
Enjoy your meal.
(Tea)
What's your plan next?
Grandmother's birthday is next month.
Planning to go back to Ye Mansion.
Time to confront them?
It had to happen someday.
Just be careful in everything.
Earlier in Suixue Pass,
someone snatched Yuan Fang from us.
And now,
someone acted
on the very same day we did,
killing Tian Feng,
Chen Fenyan, and Lu Zhi.
Someone else is targeting
Marquis Muyang behind the scenes.
Perhaps we're being watched too.
I'll be careful.
Still found nothing
about those people at the Suixue Pass.
They retreat and advance with discipline,
and are quite strong fighters.
If we can identify them,
round them all up.
But without any leads,
they aren't our top priority.
For now, they are not our enemies.
Let them be
as long as they don't hinder us.
Do you think
those who killed
Tian Feng and the other two
could be the same group
we encountered at the Suixue Pass?
Are they all working
for the young emperor?
Not really.
Who else then?
Can't be the Empress Dowager's faction
fighting among themselves.
In the court today,
besides the Emperor
and the Empress Dowager's forces,
it must be the influence
of Duke Hua's faction.
Tian Feng and his men
served Marquis Muyang.
Now they're dead.
Whoever benefits most from this
was the mastermind behind this matter.
Makes sense.
Right.
I found a new place
to settle in the capital.
No need to send messages
to the Ye Mansion if you want me.
You're leaving the Ye Mansion?
Aren't you the head of their security?
Head of security is nothing special.
The beds at Ye Mansion are too hard.
The bedding is damp.
And food is bland every day.
Because of you,
I infiltrated into the Ye Mansion.
Three years through heat and cold
was really hard work.
Now that business is done,
time for me to find
somewhere else to settle.
So where's the new place?
Xiangqi Pavilion.
Xiangqi Pavilion?
Master Guan would tan your hide
if he knew it.
He was wilder than me
back when he was young.
Really?
Qingshuang,
is Master Guan really that sort?
I don't know.
Qingshuang
is here too?
Of course.
Li.
Have you been settling in alright
at Prince Ding's Mansion?
I've been fine.
What about Qingshuang?
Has she gotten used to it?
Why couldn't she?
Senior brother.
What you should be worrying about
isn't Qingshuang, but yourself.
Now Lu Changfu is dead.
He was burned alive inside the palace.
That'd definitely attract scrutiny.
Living in such a flaunting place
like Xiangqi Pavilion,
you should be extra careful.
I know it.
You also need to be careful.
That Prince Ding isn't one
to underestimate.
Rest easy. We're getting along fine.
Really?
Really.
Before leaving Lishan,
I asked Senior He to divine my fortune.
He said that Prince Ding and I
will get along well
and have many heirs.
Well then,
how's Senior He?
He's been fine,
but always worrying about
the tree in front of his house.
He told me many times
to help him
cut that tree down during this trip.
Let's go.
Excuse me,
check.
Your Highness.
What's the noise outside?
Who's here?
It's His Highness's friend.
In the front courtyard.
A friend?
Ding says
it's Feng Zhiyao
from Qingfeng Mingyue Tower.
He's here to borrow a horse.
I'll go check.
Your Highness.
Shouldn't you freshen up a bit
before meeting guests?
Alright.
But do hurry.
Jingfan isn't spirited enough.
I want your Lieyun.
You can't manage Lieyun.
Ridiculous!
If you can, why wouldn't I?
Jingfan is Lieyun's colt.
I won't ride the son.
I want its father.
Master Feng.
Lieyun was raised
on desert wind and sand.
It recognizes its master.
Last year, it bit
a Hu merchant's arm in West Market.
Be careful not to get hurt.
Tomorrow's the polo match.
I need a fine steed.
Don't be stingy.
Back then, it fought through
three towns in Cangbei.
Tomorrow, I'll ride it
and score three consecutive goals
on the polo field.
Mo Lao'er.
Help me!
Don't just watch me there!
Get out of the way!
Are you alright?
I'm fine.
Good.
Let's go.
I'm not fine.
(Day and Night Diligence)
You know what?
The Princess Consort
suits you rather well.
Let me use it.
I'll go meet your Princess Consort.
It's nothing, just a scratch.
How can it be nothing?
Look, it's bleeding.
You told me to meet guests
after freshening up.
I didn't expect
Master Feng's horsemanship
to be so mediocre.
He dared to ride His Highness's horse?
Overestimating himself.
I am Feng Zhiyao
from Qingfeng Mingyue Tower.
Pleased to meet you.
You got injured today because of me.
I felt quite guilty about it,
so I brought ointment for you.
You were gossiping about me
behind my back?
Someone like him
won't hold it against you.
Apologize to Master Feng.
- Pardon my offense.
- It's alright.
Just joking.
Please.
Thank you.
This Ice Toad Ointment
is excellent for healing wounds.
I'll gift you
a set of twelve colors rouge
as a compensation tomorrow.
I'll take the ointment,
but not the rouge. I don't need it.
Fine.
Since you accept this ointment,
I'll assume you accepted my apology.
Rouge isn't essential, anyway.
However,
I could give you a formula.
What kind of formula?
A secret formula to cure
His Highness's peculiar temper.
Please tell.
His Highness
has gotten used
to being alone over the years.
He needs a beautiful wife like you.
In my opinion,
let him spend less time indoors
and take him out more to experience
the hustle and bustle of ordinary life.
Then his peculiar temper will fade away.
His Highness
is such a well-behaved person.
Master Feng, don't lead him astray.
He doesn't need my lead.
His Highness is as cunning
as a squid, full of schemes.
See?
Next time you gossip
behind someone's back,
keep your voice down.
Farewell.
♪Huainan rice fills tribute boats♪
♪Longyou grapes inebriate royal towers♪
♪A hundred performances are staged
on the Linde Hall♪
Sigh over a hundred years?
These lyrics likely originate
from Lishan, don't they?
Lishan?
It has been many years
since I met old acquaintances.
Are you thinking of Wanzhou?
Back then, we had no choice.
It was good for Wanzhou
to stay at Lishan.
How are things at Prince Ding's Mansion?
They've been married for some time now.
Your Majesty,
the Princess Consort
has been relatively idle lately.
Ms. Wen
has been living a reclusive life.
I heard
she refused to see the Princess Consort
the first day after the wedding.
Would you like to meet her?
(Shende Shop)
We've suffered a significant loss.
Sorry for that.
In recent years, the common people
have mostly practiced frugality.
The porcelain market
in the capital is indeed depressed.
My luck hasn't been good either.
Some days ago,
a boatload of fabrics
to Yangzhou got ruined.
The boat capsized,
and the fabrics were all lost.
Indeed.
I'm having my unlucky year.
Your Highness,
my shop is located in
the most remote corner of East Market.
It rarely sees customers on normal days.
Plus, much of the stored grain
has spoiled,
hence the losses.
The antique shop business is tough.
Your Highness.
I feel deeply ashamed.
I hope to resign from this position.
Yes, Your Highness.
We aren't
cut out for this steward position.
I think you should handle it yourself.
You hail from Lishan,
full of learning and wisdom.
Surely you have the means
to manage the shops properly,
turning losses into profits.
Yes.
After quitting your jobs,
where do you all intend to go?
My son is about to take the civil exams.
I must go be with him.
My parents are getting on in years,
so I must go be with them.
I've been worn out lately,
and want to travel around
to unwind.
Right.
I've been in the capital
for several years.
And now,
I found my loved one.
I plan to get married.
You even found love
in managing the shop?
It shows this shop
has quite auspicious Feng Shui.
I see.
Running a business is challenging.
These past years, you have worked hard.
Not at all.
Grandfather once taught me
to treat meritorious people well.
I will remember
your loyalty and dedication.
You flatter me.
Before I leave,
Master Zhu entrusted me with
this recommendation letter
for Steward Yang's son.
He asked me to deliver it to Lord Zhou,
who oversees this year's civil exams.
Your son is Master Zhu's last disciple.
I bet Lord Zhou would look after him.
Impossible!
How could my son
be Master Zhu's disciple?
Back in Yangzhou,
you curried favor with a fellow villager
of Master Zhu to secure admission.
Master Zhu is a literary authority.
Would he lie just
to claim a relationship with you?
Mind your words.
Lishan's current status is uncertain.
You are jeopardizing
my son's career path.
You should be the one
to mind your words.
Lishan has sealed its gate
just to compile texts.
The palace guards have been stationed
to keep the tranquility of the mountain.
You rashly presume imperial intentions,
trying to condemn Lishan.
This is a grave offense.
Steward Wang.
Over these years, those
on the mountain have lacked food.
Thank you for frequently
sending rice and provisions there.
N-Not me.
I never did that.
Lishan Mountain
is heavily guarded.
How could I possibly send anything?
Your Highness.
Don't slander me.
This could cost me my life!
The teachers on the mountain
can all attest to this.
Wait, impossible!
Impossible!
Steward Zhou.
What do you think?
Your Highness,
I might've took the wrong ledger.
I'll review accounts again
and get you a detailed ledger.
You must account
for everything carefully.
Otherwise,
he'll break your legs.
Yes.
How about you guys?
Perhaps we made a mistake.
We'll go back and check.
- Right!
Let's go.
Well...
Hurry.
Let's go.
I told you we shouldn't do so.
Exactly.
Your Highness.
We have no steward now.
I have a candidate in mind.
Wei Zhuang.
Zhuang.
- Aunt Wang.
- Wonderful news!
Someone sent you a job offer,
asking you to be steward.
A job offer?
Which shop?
Shende Shop.
I heard from my husband
that the items there
are all worth a fortune.
Just a water cup this big alone
can fetch fifty string.
If Wei Zhuang can secure
this steward position,
your family's hardships
would finally be over.
(Employment Contract
for Shende Shop Steward)
(Shende Shop)
You need a steward?
Yes.
Your Highness,
want to eat something?
Even for composing a new piece,
you shouldn't play for days without rest.
How can your body handle this?
Your Highness.
An imperial decree
requires you and His Highness
to enter tomorrow.
His Highness and I?
Yes.
Along with Prince Ding
and Princess Ding.
You're still up?
We're about to enter
the palace tomorrow.
Yet you can sleep soundly?
We'll go meet
the Empress Dowager tomorrow,
so I should rest early,
regulate my breath
and perform well tomorrow.
I didn't expect
you would be so carefree.
Should I be nervous?
Lishan Academy has been
neglected for eight years.
The Empress Dowager
suddenly summons you.
Shouldn't you be nervous?
Lishan Academy has been closed for years
without receiving the emperor's summons,
because it's been
compiling texts these years.
But I think
the Empress Dowager has never forgotten
the teachers on Lishan Mountain,
Otherwise, she wouldn't dispatch guards
to protect Lishan's tranquility.
Do you truly think so?
I have admired the Empress Dowager
since childhood
and often met the Empress Dowager
with my mom.
The Empress Dowager bestowed upon me
palace-exclusive Jiuchong cakes
and Guifei fruits.
She has shown kindness
to my mom and me.
So, I have nothing to nervous about.
In that case,
rest early.
Your Highness.
Take it easy.
I didn't sleep well last night
and woke up late.
Sorry.
Let's go.
Let me do it.
Your Highness.
Let me handle this menial task.
It's nothing.
Let's go.
So heavy.
(Pastry)
Li, slow down.
Your Majesty.
Li.
Your Majesty, I've missed you so much.
You've grown taller.
Wanzhou.
Mom.
It's been years.
Have you settled back
into life in the capital?
Very well.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Your maternal grandfather, Headmaster Xu,
was once my teacher too.
How has he been?
And how are the other teachers?
Your Majesty,
they're all well.
Grandfather is in good health,
busy compiling texts.
Knowing I was coming down the mountain,
he asked me to convey his regards to you.
The other teachers are well too.
They teach lessons
and assign coursework diligently.
What lessons are taught there now?
Astronomy, calendrics,
I Ching and numerology.
All are included.
Grandfather also instructs scholars
to stay informed on current affairs.
Really?
How does he teach these?
While proofing and annotating
the Treatise on Rivers and Waterways,
he often mentioned your remarkable feat
of changing the canal transport method
back then.
Knowing after the rerouting,
thirty-thousand fewer trackers
were conscripted,
and taxes were reduced by forty percent,
the teachers all say you demonstrate
extraordinary governance talent,
and deeply admire you.
(Preview)
Your Highness.
Is Her Highness planning
to steal a tree?
Who's there?
Tree thief!
Stop!
Why cut a tree?
Could we talk inside?
Now you're embarrassed?
There's plenty of mud on your shoes.
What?
The trip from the Mansion to Shende Shop
is that challenging?
I went to help Wuyou fight.
♪Memories hold you back
from fulfilling your dreams♪
♪Only by moving forward
can you find reunion♪
♪Endings only mark new routes♪
♪It's all part of the scenery♪
♪To the horizon's call♪
♪Your journey hasn't started♪
♪Towards mountains,
chase the stars bright♪
♪Both joy and grief
make the trip worthwhile♪
♪Trying to catch up
to your own lost shadow♪
♪Within the wilds, echoes thrive♪
♪Clear mind leads to a clear path♪
♪Be grateful to your losses♪
♪Make your steps weightless♪
♪Towards mountains,
chase the stars bright♪
♪Let time embrace you
and wash away the past♪
♪Put every twist behind you,
drift leisurely through time♪
♪Make headway against the wind,
let mountains bow to your pace♪
♪Rush towards a life without regret♪
♪Let your nature burst free♪
♪Unbound by form♪